(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
THE FOLLOWING CONTENT CONTAINS DEPICTIONS
OF DOMESTIC ABUSE.
VIEWER DISCRETION IS ADVISED.
[Heeju breathing heavily]
Aren't you tired? Huh?
Why don't you come sit down?
Let's talk a little
and figure this out.
[Heeju breathing heavily]
If you give me the gold bar
and the knife, we can talk.
Ugh, you're being really annoying.
[exhales]
[panicked breathing]
[gold bars clanging]
Closer.
[scraping across floor]
And the knife.
[clatters]
[panicked breathing]
[exhales sharply]
[relieved exhale]
[Woogy] You need to think about this
from an economic perspective, okay?
It really doesn't matter
if it's gold or drugs.
[Woogy] All that matters
is raking in the dough.
Can we turn that item into money or not?
You really think taking the gold bar
to a jewelry shop's a good idea?
[Woogy] A 10-kilogram bar
with a foreign stamp on it?
[exhales]
Okay, just listen.
The jewelry shops, the pawn shops even,
they're all linked to who I work for.
[Woogy] Stuff like gold bars,
that's gonna get around.
You wanna sell a gold bar,
you gotta hand over your phone number,
name, and ID.
So what?
You'll write down,
"Kim Heeju, ID 123?"
You think you can handle all this alone?
You can't.
But I can.
I'm telling you.
My methods are solid.
How do we do it, then?
[exhales sharply]
You a bit more interested now?
Okay, before I lay all this out,
let's make a deal.
-Hey, get back!
-[Woogy] Like partners.
[Heeju] I said get back. Go.
Talk from there.
[exhales sharply]
[Woogy mumbling]
Okay, first, where's the casket?
[Woogy] This can't be everything.
Just tell me where it is.
I need to know exactly
how many bars there are
before I can put a plan together.
Why should I even trust you?
I literally just told you!
If I was gonna rat you out to the boss,
I would have done it already,
and all the guys would be here.
Fine, I wasn't gonna tell you this.
Guess I have to, though.
Look.
[Woogy] That shit hurt.
It still hurts.
They were gonna cut off my ear
if I didn't start talking.
But I held out.
[Woogy] You know why?
'Cause I thought of you.
[exhales]
What the hell?
Why am I such a softie?
[Heeju] Don't make me laugh.
The only reason you showed up here
was to look for the drugs.
If you couldn't find them
you would have threatened me
or done whatever it took
to make me talk.
And once you found them,
you would have killed me.
Oh, really?
Correct me if I'm wrong here,
but you were the one threatening
to shoot me.
Okay, I get it.
Let's move on.
[Woogy] How about this?
Don't tell me where to find the gold.
[Woogy] I won't ask, either.
If you think I'd kill you
and make a run for it after finding out
where the gold is, don't tell me.
[Woogy] If I have no idea,
there's no problem, right?
Instead, how's this?
Every three days,
you give me one gold bar.
[Woogy] Then it'll be up to me
to sell it and bring you the cash.
That means I won't be able
to pull anything funny
until we've sold all the gold.
Make sense?
[Woogy] How many are there?
That I need to know.
[strained breathing]
There's ten.
[Woogy] Ten?
If we sell one for a billion,
times ten is ten billion.
Split it in half.
-[Woogy] Five billion each.
-Split it?
[exhales]
[Heeju] You think it's just you and me?
STYLE
::cue()
It's not our gold.
It belongs to Dokyung.
What? Lee Dokyung?
Nah, he's gonna die soon.
[Woogy] And even if he lives,
he's going to jail anyway.
Wait, why not just cut him out?
What'd you say?
Oh.
What, are you dating?
Am I right?
Is he your boyfriend?
-[groans]
-[Woogy] Eh, doesn't matter.
How is it Lee Dokyung's?
You realize he stole it, right?
So it really belongs to Chairman An.
[Heeju] Okay, then.
[Heeju] So the three of us will split it.
You'll get exactly one-third of the money.
That's your share.
Okay.
Okay!
[exhales sharply]
-So, then.
-[Heeju] What?
-[Woogy] We should fist bump so that...
-Don't come any closer!
Well, we gotta lock in our contract, so...
...fist bump to seal the deal.
First you have to tell me how you plan
on selling the gold bars.
Explain that.
Then I'll decide.
[exhales sharply]
Are you serious?
What the...
[Woogy] Fine. Listen carefully.
[Woogy] Gold is traded in hundreds
of forms in shops across the country.
Gold rings, gold pigs, random stuff.
And the gold bar.
The one-kilogram bars are the easiest ones
for us to trade.
Everything changes depending on
the weight, purity,
and where it was manufactured.
So first we gotta break these down
into one-kilo bars
-and recast them.
-[Heeju] Who can do that?
-[Heeju] You?
-[Woogy] No.
We'll obviously need a goldsmith for that.
Then there's the actual sale.
Selling a 10-kilo bar would be hard,
but small ones, well,
jewelry stores have
no problem buying those.
All of Gwangwon-do has ties to our company
so that won't work.
I'll have to go to jewelry stores
in other areas
and sell only one bar per store.
The whole process of recasting
a bar to selling it
shouldn't take any more than, say,
three days.
So selling them all should take a month.
And to avoid being tracked by the cops,
we gotta make all
of our transactions in cash.
Not to mention, we'll need fake IDs,
burner phones, and burner bank accounts.
But I'll be taking care of all that,
so don't you worry about a thing.
SAMJIN GOLD EXCHANGE
And Heeju,
let's make one thing clear.
[Woogy] Until we've sold all ten gold bars
and split the cash,
we trust each other.
[Woogy] Never, seriously never...
Ever, ever, ever,
never betray each other.
[Woogy] Do you promise?
If not, we're both dead.
You'll be discovered in that mining town
hanging from your neck.
And as for me,
I'm screwing the company over, too,
so I'll get something chopped off
and become a cripple.
You know what I'm saying?
[exhales]
You're the one I'm worried about.
[exhales sharply]
[Woogy] Okay.
[Woogy grunts]
Do this to sign the contract.
Hmm? Deal?
You gotta say "deal" when you do it.
That's how it works.
Deal.
[scoffs]
[exhales sharply]
[exhales]
[Woogy] Finally.
[♪ tense music]
STYLE
::cue()
[♪ tense music continues]
[crows cawing]
EPISODE 3
PARTNERSHIP
[Jinman] Yeah.
[clears throat]
[Jinman groans]
Goodness.
[Jinman clears throat]
[metal creaking]
[chains rattling]
[Jinman] Careful.
Ugh, shit.
[camera shutter clicks]
SEOYOON, YERIN, I'M SORRY FOR GOING FIRST.
TO EVERYONE WHO WAS HARMED BECAUSE OF ME,
I AM SORRY. THIS IS THE LAST CHOICE
I CAN MAKE. I'M SORRY. I'M SO SORRY.
Hold up. Stop.
[camera shutter clicks]
[indistinct chatter]
Go, yeah.
Should I send him to forensics?
Nah, just the morgue is fine.
-Yes, sir.
-Yeah.
-[Male Police Officer] The morgue.
-[groans]
[clicks tongue, clears throat]
[cell phone vibrating]
-Take him to the morgue.
-[Male Police Officer] Understood.
[cell phone vibrating]
[exhales]
Ah, I did it. Yeah.
I took care of it like you asked.
Who wrote that note, though?
Looked like President Go's handwriting.
You gotta stop with all
these useless theatrics.
It's a waste.
Just keep your guys in line.
[Hocheol] Thanks for your work.
See you soon, Detective.
Sounds good.
[cell phone beeps]
GANGWON SAEBAEK HOSPITAL
[machine rumbling]
[Sunok exhales]
What the hell have we been doing all day?
We left the shop unattended.
[Female Nurse] Ms. Yeo Sunok.
Here. Come on.
[Male Doctor grunts]
[Male Doctor] Hello.
Could the patient wait outside?
I'd like to speak with the guardian first.
-Uh...
-You can just talk.
I already know anyway.
[all exhaling sharply]
You were diagnosed here a year ago,
but you never went to another hospital?
-No.
-[Male Doctor groans]
[Male Doctor] We should
have started treatment then.
We're a little late now.
If you look here,
you'll see that the tumor cells
have metastasized to the lungs.
[Sunok grunts]
[Male Doctor] Were you feeling okay?
I imagine the pain would be quite severe.
Could surgery be an option?
She should get hospitalized first.
I recommend an examination,
then beginning chemotherapy
to slow down the metastasis.
[Male Doctor] As for surgery,
let's see how things progress
and then decide.
-'Kay.
-So my cancer's in the final stage.
Wouldn't surgery be useless?
[Male Doctor exhales sharply]
Well, when it comes to stages,
you could say that, however...
How much longer do I have?
A specific time frame
is hard to determine at this point.
If I get treatment, I can live...
...how much longer?
Into my 80s?
-Auntie.
-[Sunok] I knew it'd be like this.
They wanna fill me with drugs...
...and poke me with needles even though
I'm dying anyway.
That's how hospitals make money, isn't it?
Hey, we're leaving.
-Auntie!
-Get up. I'm done with all this.
Auntie, please wait! Seriously!
[exhales sharply]
STYLE
::cue()
-Auntie.
-Just forget it.
Oh, come on, please!
I said forget it!
These guys are all crooks.
They don't deserve our hard-earned money.
If this is really about the money,
don't worry.
-I have it.
-[Sunok] Where? Show me.
I wanna see some before I die.
[groaning]
Aren't you in a lot of pain right now?
This is about more than
just you living longer.
Come on.
You're not dead yet.
At least let them give you something
to ease the pain while you're still alive.
Since when did you worry
about me like this?
You were the one who ran off
to live your own life.
And now that I'm dying,
you suddenly have a sense of duty?
You're the one who needs to have
a sense of duty.
What kind of mother wants to just die
and leave their kid by themself?
Am I your mother?
Well, aren't you?
You gave birth to me.
[Sunok] You think I had you
'cause I wanted to?
[exhales sharply]
[sighs]
[bus engine rumbling]
[engine revving]
WELCOME TO GOLD LAND
THE CITY OF DREAMS AND HOPES
[Jinman groans]
[humming]
Hey.
Yeah...
[Jinman] What's this?
I expected a nice spread.
[Jinman] Ah, come on.
Guess not.
So disappointing.
[Jinman] Anyway, I guess the chairman
isn't back from overseas.
I must say, you're looking great.
[Jinman] It must be fun playing
the chairman.
[Hocheol] Lee Dokyung's cell phone.
[Hocheol] Same guy you were tracking
a few days ago.
-Does that mean he's dead?
-[Hocheol] No, he's in the hospital.
But now the cops are on his tail.
Hence our little meeting here.
Not much I can do.
Not if the police are on him. No way.
I'm not asking you to do anything
to Lee Dokyung.
Just take this phone
and use it to find a person.
No way he's working alone.
He's got an accomplice.
A stupid fuck who took off with
the van carrying all of our stuff.
[inhales]
Ah, the casket.
Ah, that must be a headache.
Just dig through his calls and texts
and see what you can find.
You can't expect me to do all that.
Come on.
Searching through
a phone like that's illegal.
And it takes too much time.
Too much money, too.
I'll give you the money,
so don't worry.
[Jinman] Oh, yeah.
Let me think about it, okay?
[Hocheol exhales sharply]
There's no time for thinking.
I gotta do this before
the chairman returns.
And when is that?
At the end of the month.
I am curious, though.
What's in the casket?
Do you know?
[Jinman] Drugs? Meth?
Organs?
Ah, you gangster assholes keep getting
into organ trafficking these days.
You just can't help yourselves.
[Hocheol] Why the fuck do you need
to know everything?
Just do what you usually do.
Do what I'm telling you.
Ah, hold on.
Do I look like the kind of guy who
just does whatever you tell him to?
Of course I'm that guy.
[Jinman] Right.
[Hocheol scoffs]
[Jinman] Fine, fine, I'll do it.
Huh?
Ah, dammit.
STYLE
::cue()
GANGWON CENTRAL POLICE AGENCY
[distant sirens blaring]
[car door opens]
Oh. Oh, there you are.
[grunting]
-Here.
-Yeah.
[coughs]
Read it, then shred it.
You leave that lying around,
you'll get audited or somethin'.
Oh. You think you're all that just 'cause
you're stationed at headquarters now?
I'm your senior.
ON-SITE INVESTIGATION REPORT
[Detective Kang] It's a burner car.
The plate number is fake, too.
Dash cam?
Nothin'.
No surveillance cams in the area, either.
So we don't know who the driver is.
Why?
The casket?
Those Geumseong guys didn't take it?
I don't think so.
What does that mean?
They either took it or they didn't.
So why do you need all this?
To keep Lee Dokyung quiet
in case he wants to talk?
-Maybe.
-Uh, wait a minute.
I'm not gonna be party to a murder.
If that's the plan then I'm done.
This is the last time I'm helping.
You can tell Park
I'm not doing this anymore.
And doing this will pay off my debts.
[distant sirens wailing]
Hey.
How big of a hole are you in?
100 million won?
Oh, man, you really poured it down
the drain, didn't you?
[groans]
What do you like to play?
Baccarat?
Ah, it won't be easy
to climb outta that hole.
What about you?
How much debt did you end up with?
10 billion won?
That's why you're still in this.
Ever since you were a patrol cop,
you've been cleaning up shit
that Geumseong leaves for you, right?
I paid them all back already.
[Detective Kang] Oh, is that so?
Well, if you're debt free then cleaning
up shit must be in your nature.
[pages flip]
-[Detective Kang exhales]
-You know what?
You're a little shit.
Better watch your mouth.
Actually...
My wife is very sick.
That so?
[Detective Kang exhales]
I'm going.
I don't want to see you again.
Hey, hey, hey.
At least tell me what's
in there before you go. Yeah?
Whatever the hell it is,
it's making the guys
at headquarters crazy.
And yet Narcotics are being awfully quiet.
So I guess it's not drugs.
Park didn't tell you anything?
Maybe he doesn't know.
Then what is it?
Come on, just tell me.
-Huh?
-[exhales]
We got the information from Interpol
and it's still under review.
You cannot leak this.
All right, all right, prick.
Gold bars.
Gold bars?
[Detective Kang] There's a Cambodian
trading company funded
by the drug cartel, Krom thom.
The word is that the chairman buried
a massive slush fund.
Under the ground.
Like, actually buried it.
-[scoffs]
-Not cash, but gold bars.
Ten tons worth.
[Detective Kang] Somehow all
this information got leaked.
And the government launched
a massive search
and seizure for tax evasion.
So all those gold bars,
they quickly moved them overseas.
One ton of 10-kilogram gold bars
per shipment,
disguised as caskets. However...
...one was found
at the airport in Hong Kong.
And apparently another one is in Korea.
And that's the casket, huh?
-The one with a ton of gold?
-Yeah, probably.
[Detective Kang] And besides,
that's the only casket that's come in
from Cambodia recently.
[crickets chirping]
[tires squeak]
[gears shift]
SEONGOGAE REST AREA
STYLE
::cue()
-Is anybody here?
-[Female Store Owner] Hi, there.
-Yes, hello.
-[Female Store Owner] Ah, yes.
Excuse me,
but the surveillance camera outside,
did you install it?
[Female Store Owner] Yes.
Well, I'm with the police. Here.
I'm Detective Kim Jinman.
I reported the installation of that camera
to the police already.
Might there be an issue?
Oh, no, no.
It's nothing like that.
There was a traffic accident out front
a few days ago.
-I just want to check something out. Yeah.
-[Female Store Owner] I see.
[mouse clicking]
[computer hard drive clicking]
[mouse clicks]
GANGWON CENTRAL POLICE AGENCY
TRAFFIC INFORMATION CENTER
-One moment. I'll take a look.
-[Jinman] Yeah.
[clicking]
[Female Police Officer] Okay.
12:29 A.M.
Jingogae Intersection.
And at 12:57 A.M.,
21 Jinbu Street.
Next, at 1:32 A.M.
National Route 59.
[Female Police Officer]
And at 1:55 A.M.,
crossing Jeongsan Bridge.
Jeongsan?
[Female Police Officer] Yes.
GEUMSEONG TOURIST HOTEL
[All] ♪ I'm begging you please
Don't cling to me anymore ♪
[Jinman] ♪ Don't come looking for me ♪
Stop it.
Ah, honey, it's fine.
Wow, what's up with your hands?
They're so pretty for a man.
Because they're woman's hands.
That means it's fine if I touch you,
right?
[Jinman] Just kidding!
♪ A heartless girl
when I'm already breaking inside ♪
Park Hocheol's here!
♪ So now just for a while... ♪
CANCEL
-[Jinman] Hey.
-What?
-I finally found my love today!
-Get him outta here.
-It's no fair!
-I know, I know.
-[Jinman] Oh, honey.
-[laughing]
[Jinman] You know, right?
My love?
Honey, I have to be really honest
with you.
Jeongah.
Sorry!
Oh, look.
Park has arrived.
[Jinman] Right when we're getting
this party started.
[door closes]
I'm taking two of those girls out with me.
-Have you found anything?
-[Jinman] Of course I did!
Wait, what did I...
You talkin' about the van?
Yeah, I've been looking around for it.
I combed through the surveillance cameras
in Gangwon-do.
I checked every single one.
Quit rambling and just spit it out.
Hey.
[Jinman] I'm taking two of them today.
-Yes, sir.
-[Jinman] Yeah? You got it?
-[Jinman] Huh?
-[Hocheol] Hey.
-Move it.
-[Jinman] Yeah.
Yeah, go get-
what are you doing?
[Jinman] Go. Get them ready.
Good.
Ah.
[Jinman] What was I saying?
[Jinman] Oh, right. The van.
Was last seen here in Jeongsan.
Where we are.
[Jinman] It was caught
on surveillance cameras.
It shows up at the entrance
to Jeongsan Bridge.
[Jinman] Then no trace of it anywhere.
And two days later,
they dump the van
at the abandoned warehouse,
but it was empty.
[Jinman] So where did they hide
the casket? Huh?
[Hocheol exhales]
[clacks on table]
Right here.
Jeongsan.
They hid it here.
So who was it, then?
The prick who was driving it?
Oh, I don't really know about that.
But either way, I've really
helped you narrow it down.
Just find out who was in Jeongsan that day
and catch 'em.
[Jinman] Wouldn't that work?
Find out quickly.
Right, but I think I got a hold
of some info that you're gonna wanna hear.
Yeah. You should know.
-[Jinman] Yeah?
-What?
I'm guessing you don't know what's in
that casket, do you?
[Jinman] Well?
You don't know, huh?
Well, I do.
[inhales sharply]
What's in it?
Well, this info's worth
at least 100 gold chips.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We can do that.
Gold bars.
[Jinman] A ton of them.
[Jinman] One ton.
The current market value...
150 billion.
[Jinman] Crazy, right?
[Jinman] But then again,
you know what's really crazy?
Is that, well, the chairman didn't
tell you you'd be smuggling gold, huh?
Why is that?
Seems like the kind of important stuff
you should know.
[Jinman] I mean,
you are his right-hand man.
[Jinman] Does that mean...
...is he demoting you?
[Jinman] Guess it doesn't matter.
[Jinman] As long as you get the job done.
STYLE
::cue()
Yeah. So.
I heard that you're one
of the best goldsmiths in the area.
Uh, yes, well...
-You've manufactured gold bars yourself?
-[Hoonseok] Yes.
[Woogy] I need you to make ten bars.
One kilo each, just like
I said on the phone.
And of course we'll provide the gold.
[Woogy] And your casting fee?
Mm...
One percent of cost.
[Woogy] Pretty good, right?
It's not every day you get
an offer like this.
[Woogy] I'm curious,
how long will it take to make them?
Around two to three days.
-Two to three.
-[Hoonseok] You see,
gold bars don't require...
[shushes]
Detailed craftsmanship.
One thing, though.
Where in Jeongsan are you from, exactly?
[Hoonseok] Don't you have a business card?
It's just that normally gold bars
are manufactured
in specific authorized factories,
so why don't you go to those?
The thing is...
There's a reason why I'm paying you such
a high fee.
It comes with one condition.
What condition, you ask?
No questions.
[Woogy] The who, what, why, where,
none of it.
They say silence is golden, right?
[Woogy] So stay silent
and you can call it a golden fee.
A golden fee?
[Woogy] Yeah, that's right.
And there's a second condition.
It's not just questions.
You can't say anything.
[Woogy] You can't go around saying,
"Hey, I'm working on this gold job.
They're 10-kilo bars,"
to literally anyone.
If you do,
our contract is over.
[Woogy] Not only that,
your life will be over.
Then you bought them illegally.
[Hoonseok] If I refuse now...
...I'll be okay, right?
Of course.
Mm, it's not like you saw
the gold or anything.
So yeah,
if you don't wanna do it,
no biggie.
It's not like anyone saw us here.
No one knows that we met to talk and-
two percent, okay?
3K per kilo.
300 million for ten bars.
[Woogy] Do you know anyone
who makes that in a month?
I wouldn't offer this to anybody else,
Hoonseok.
I like your face.
[Woogy] You look like the type of guy
who'd make gold bars with total precision.
I really want to work with you, okay?
But if you'd rather refuse, say so, hmm?
I'm a busy man.
I have to go look for someone else now.
-We're done here.
-[Hoonseok] The gold bar.
Show me.
Then I'll decide.
Okay.
Here. This is it.
[Hoonseok] Okay.
[Woogy sniffs]
Here he is.
Mr. Lee Hoonseok.
Yeah.
And this is, uh...
Call her Boss.
Nice to meet you, Boss.
Hello.
[Woogy] He's going to work with us.
He'll make the...
You know what?
I've noticed your voice is kind of loud,
so from now on we'll call
the gold bars "potatoes," okay?
Show him the potato.
[Woogy] He wants to check it.
STYLE
::cue()
Hey, it's okay.
You're good to show him.
[Woogy] We're all in the same boat now
so it's cool.
[bag rustling and unzipping]
[Heeju grunts]
[both grunting]
Here.
[Woogy grunts]
[exhales sharply]
[scraping]
This is real.
Well, of course it is.
It's the real deal.
All right, I'll have it done.
It won't take long.
Come back tomorrow night.
Uh, no, no, no.
It'd be better...
[grunts]
[Heeju] ...if you could start work today.
-[Heeju] And I would like to supervise.
-[grunts]
That's right. And while she's watching,
I'll also be watching.
I can't do it right away.
I need to get things like
a new crucible and new molds,
and if we're stamping
the Korea Mint mark...
I can wait.
[Woogy] Yeah, yeah.
We can wait.
Hey, you can understand
why she's suspicious.
You can get all those things today, right?
Then we can get started tonight, huh?
Pull an all-nighter?
How about this?
Midnight tonight.
Come to the front of the workshop.
When everything's all set,
I'll give you guys a call.
-And I'll let you inside.
-[Woogy] Nice.
[Heeju] All right.
So I'll call you later.
-See you at midnight.
-Mm-hmm.
Call us. Call us later.
[car door closes]
[exhales sharply]
[Woogy] See?
What'd I say?
There's nothing money can't buy.
Do you really think he's the right guy?
He seems too nice.
So? What's wrong with being a nice guy?
[Heeju] He could have a sudden change
of heart
and decide to report us to the police.
Stop worrying about that.
I told you I did
a background check on the guy.
That guy there?
He lives with his widowed mother
and sister.
He's the breadwinner of the family.
So what?
[exhales sharply]
Heeju.
This is how we make deals in my world,
okay?
Money's important
but collateral's necessary.
It's absolutely essential.
Last thing you want
is to get stabbed in the back.
So you always have to consider
the worst-case scenario.
And these guys?
What's the one thing that keeps them
from doing something stupid or crazy?
Collateral, of course.
The more important the collateral is,
the less likely they are
to screw us over.
So you're saying...
...his mom and younger sister
are collateral?
-Ah, come on. You know what I mean.
-[Heeju] Then what's my collateral?
Is it my aunt?
Heeju.
That's why you went to the pawn shop
the other day.
To check on my collateral?
Are you seriously asking me that?
I went because I wanted to see Auntie.
You got it all wrong.
It's not like that.
Ah, come on.
Collateral's insane.
How 'bout we go eat?
What do you want?
[grunts]
Bokjiri sounds good..
STYLE
::cue()
[crickets chirping]
[Heeju] Something's wrong.
Give him a call.
[Woogy] Well, he said he'd call
when he's ready.
[cell phone vibrates]
Yeah?
Mm, okay.
[Woogy grunting]
[breathing heavily]
JEIL WORKSHOP
[keypad beeping]
[door locks unlocking]
[door squeaks]
[light switches click]
[whirring]
[door locks beeping]
Oh, here.
Oh.
[Woogy] I got it.
Here.
[both grunting]
[gold bar thuds]
[zipper unzips]
How long will it take?
I'll be done with it before morning.
I guess you two just wait here.
Yeah, and don't you even think
about pulling any stunts.
I'll be watching you.
[Woogy] I'm watching you over there, too!
[scraping]
[exhales sharply]
[heat hissing]
[exhales]
[bar clinking]
[hissing]
[door clangs]
[fire roars]
[flames hissing]
[melted gold splatting]
[flames hiss]
[gold clinks]
[water sizzling]
[bars clink]
[flames roaring]
[cell phone vibrating]
INCOMING CALL
JEIL WORKSHOP PRESIDENT NOH
JEWELRY ECONOMY DAILY
[distant gold clinking]
[exhales]
That's right.
You went into that coal mine.
[distant thunder rumbling]
[thunder cracks]
DAD! BE SAFE AGAIN TODAY
You were there?
Of course I was.
[exhales]
[inhales and exhales sharply]
What was the name of that mutt, again?
[Woogy] Mongsil or something.
Don't you remember?
You went in there while we
were playing freeze tag, I think.
[Woogy] You were looking
for that stupid dog
and I waited for you forever.
[newspaper page turns]
I kept waiting,
but you didn't come out.
So I went to get the Aunties.
[9-Year-Old Heeju] Mongsil, wait!
STYLE
::cue()
[dog yaps]
[9-Year-Old Heeju] Mongsil!
[distant dog yaps]
Mongsil!
Mongsil, here!
[9-Year-Old Heeju] Mongsil!
Heeju.
[Woogy] You don't remember?
[exhales]
I'm not sure.
I don't think so.
You really forgot.
[Woogy] Come on.
You gotta remember.
I practically saved your life, you know?
[Heeju] I don't know.
[Heeju] I seriously don't remember.
[Woogy exhales sharply]
[sighs]
[cell phone vibrating]
[door lock beeping]
[chiming]
[door handle rattles]
Hoonseok?
[gasps and shushes]
-[Hoonseok] Shh, quiet. Quiet.
-[President Noh] Are you there?
Who is it?
[Woogy] Hey! What are you doing?
It's-it's the owner.
[all gasping]
Hold on.
[gold clinking]
Hoonseok!
Quick, come on.
-Come on.
-[President Noh] Are you asleep?
[gasps]
[President Noh] Hoonseok.
[locks clacking]
Ah, goodness.
So you were in here.
Yes. What are you...
Well, why did you lock the door?
What are you doing up at this hour?
Uh, sir, can I talk to you for a sec?
Hold on.
[Hoonseok] There's nothing...
[Hoonseok] Sir?
Wait.
What-what's all that?
-[nervous exhale]
-[President Noh] Spit it out!
[President Noh] What are you up to?
[Hoonseok] Someone from Janggak asked me
to do some craft work.
Let go.
[both grunting]
[President Noh] What? Seems like a lot.
[Hoonseok] It's 14k.
There's not much gold in it.
[Hoonseok] Hold on, sir!
Why do you wanna go in there?
[Hoonseok] There's nothing to...
Goodness, what's with you?
[President Noh grunts]
What are you doing at this hour?
Why aren't you at home sleeping?
[President Noh groans]
I couldn't sleep.
[exhales sharply]
I decided to sell this factory
to President Choi.
[President Noh]
It's best you stop working here...
...and look somewhere else.
But sir...
I'm very sorry.
I wanted to help you send your sister
to college.
And of course I wanted to help your mom.
Make sure you could take care
of her while she's unwell.
[President Noh] But there's just
no way I can hold on anymore.
Forget about me.
What are you going
to do about paying off your loan?
I thought you said Mr. Choi's offer
wasn't that great.
[chuckles]
Look, I wasn't good enough.
[President Noh] That's why I'm in debt.
What can you do?
[President Noh exhales sharply]
Okay.
Be careful.
I hear there are a lot
of thieves stealing gold dust.
Better keep the doors locked up.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You've always been a hard worker.
[chuckles]
[exhales]
[relieved exhale]
STYLE
::cue()
[gold bar clatters]
[both gasp]
[clanging]
Wait a minute.
What was that noise?
Uh, what noise?
I didn't hear any noise.
-What's wrong with you?
-[Hoonseok] Nothing.
Get out of my way, kid!
-[President Noh] What was that?
-[Hoonseok] That was nothing!
-[Hoonseok] You should just go...
-I'm going in!
Sir, wait, please!
Don't go in there!
[all shouting]
[blow lands]
[all yelling]
We're fucked.
We're so fucked.
Sir, are you okay?
Why'd you do that?
[Heeju] He needs to go to the hospital.
[Heeju] We have to take him, okay?
[Heeju] Woogy. Hey. Hey!
What are you doing?
We have no choice.
He saw the gold bar
so I gotta finish him off.
-No!
-[Hoonseok] Are you crazy?
-[both grunting]
-Let go.
Let go!
[Heeju] Wait! Wait a second!
Just-just put that down, okay?
If you don't wanna help,
get out of the way.
-[Woogy] I gotta cut him into pieces.
-No! You can't do that, no!
[Heeju] Cut him up?
-He's alive still!
-[Woogy] Is he?
I guess I just have to kill him, then!
You want the gold?
[Woogy] Then fucking move!
-No, you can't! You can't!
-[Woogy] Get off!
[Hoonseok] I can talk to him!
I can say you were thieves!
He won't know about the gold!
[Heeju] Yeah! L-let him take him
to the hospital.
After that, we can let
Hoonseok take care of it.
Enough. Move out of the way.
[all shouting]
If you kill my boss,
then you'll have to kill me, too!
Or else I'll spill everything I know!
[Heeju] If you do this,
then you and I are through!
You gonna kill me as well?
[all breathing heavily]
[Heeju] Woogy. Woogy, please.
You always used to listen to me.
[Heeju] When we were kids.
[Heeju] At the coal mine.
And I fell down.
It was you who saved me, right?
[both breathing heavily]
That's right.
I remember.
It's just...
...I didn't wanna remember it.
Fuck.
[tool clanging]
[relieved heavy breaths]
-Whoa, no!
-[Woogy] Hey! What?
We're taking him to the hospital, right?
[Hoonseok] Wait, wait, wait!
Behind your back, you-you have a knife.
[Woogy exhales sharply]
Fuck.
[strained breathing]
Ah, fuck these damn
conscientious assholes.
[labored breathing]
[Woogy] Oh, what the fuck am I doing?
[Woogy breathing heavily]
[Woogy] Is this even right?
[Woogy] Ah, what is this shit? Ah!
[electricity buzzing]
[machines rumbling]
[metal clangs]
[hammer clinking]
[gold bars clinking]
STYLE
::cue()
[clinking]
[Hoonseok] Okay.
If they're off by point-one gram,
there's no need to worry.
That's within the normal weight range,
so you'll sell them without any issues.
As for the leftover dust and fragments,
I'll keep them here,
and I'll mix them in when I do
the next casting.
[Heeju exhales]
Thank you so much.
You did good work.
Nice work.
I'll be back in three days, 'kay?
And the cash?
[Woogy] Didn't we tell you?
You didn't tell him?
What?
Well, it's a deferred payment.
[Woogy] I'll settle it in three days.
[Hoonseok] Wait, wait, wait.
Wait a minute.
Uh, deferred?
Come on.
Shit, you don't trust us?
Of course I don't trust you!
How do I know you two will actually
come back in three days?
Well, what do you want?
[Woogy] I don't have it!
I don't have the cash!
Hold on. We-we agreed
to give you two percent, didn't we?
Yeah.
[Heeju] Well, this...
[grunts]
...is worth 150 mil.
[Heeju] Consider this half upfront.
And you'll get the rest once
the job is done.
Oh.
Wow. You really scored.
Lucky you.
Give it to me.
I'll exchange it for you.
No, thanks.
I can take care of it myself.
And you'll promise us that you'll be able
to work on the rest, too?
Yes, Boss.
I'll do it because I trust you.
[relieved exhale]
But I don't trust him at all.
You motherfucker. You think you can point
your finger and say that shit to my face?
[Woogy] Who the fuck do you think you are?
-You wanna die?
-See you next time.
What a piece of shit.
Hey, hey!
[Woogy] I don't trust you either, you
prick!
-[Woogy] Where's my knife? No!
-[Heeju] Stop it. Come on. Come on.
Sorry.
I got worked up earlier.
The whole situation kinda got out
of control.
Do you need a doctor?
Forget it.
Instead, I need your word.
If you and I are going to work together,
you won't kill anyone.
[Heeju] If you ever pull a knife
or spill blood one more time,
you and I are done.
It's over.
[Woogy scoffs]
What if someone finds out
we're doing this?
[inhales and exhales sharply]
You think you're being
fucking conscientious?
Hmm?
That mindset doesn't make
any fucking sense
for a wannabe thief.
[Woogy] Fuck.
You're stealing gold, you know.
A whopping 100 kilograms
of someone else's gold.
And now you want the money?
All in good conscience?
[Woogy] Without getting blood
on your hands?
[exhales sharply]
Well, then.
Do you promise or not?
[exhales sharply]
Yeah, I'll do my best.
[♪ dramatic music]
[Woogy] Here.
STYLE
::cue()
[exhales]
[distant birds chirping]
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[door creaks open]
[Heeju gasps]
[shuddering]
[Sunok] How much longer
are you gonna sleep?
It's already dark out.
Keep still.
[Sunok] Almost done.
Go.
Get out of here.
[Sunok] Run away.
I'll pay off all of your debt for you.
Do you even have the money
to pay off my debt?
You don't even know what I owe.
How much is it?
[exhales sharply]
I don't have debt.
When it's time, I'll leave quietly.
Don't worry.
Where were you last night?
Were you hanging out with that thug?
-What on Earth did you do with your hand?
-I already told you,
there's nothing going on!
And my hand...
I just fell, okay?
Don't tell me it was from a fall!
It was from a knife.
Enough, all right.
Wow. You luckless bitch.
[surprised exhale]
You ran away and still ended up like this.
[both exhale]
You wanna know what's really ridiculous?
Everyone can tell that the bitch
with the worst luck is you.
So hearing you call me that
just makes me furious.
It really pisses me off.
Don't put all your trust
into men like that.
One moment can ruin your whole life.
You're one to talk.
Then why did you marry that trash?
[Sunok] To survive.
You think I could pay off my debt
and raise a kid by serving coffee?
-If it weren't for you I would've...
-[Heeju] Don't use me as an excuse!
I never asked for any of that!
Every single moment I had to spend
with that man was nothing but hell!
An do you think I was happy?
That's why I begged you to run away!
[Heeju] You didn't wanna go, though!
[Heeju] Even after I told you what
that man tried to do to me, you...
[Sunok] What is the point
of dredging this up now?
Should I beg for your forgiveness?
-Would that make it better?
-[Heeju] Yes!
Beg and apologize.
So I can feel better.
[labored breathing]
[door opens and closes]
[whimpering]
[crying]
[pills rattling]
[panicked breathing]
[Sunok] Heeju, Heeju.
Don't come out.
[Sunok] Your uncle is here.
[door closes]
[door opens]
Well? You glad to see me?
It's been two months.
Uh, I was about to close up here.
[Sunok] Let's go home.
Did you eat?
[Cheoljung] Get in here already.
Hi. It's me again.
[chuckles]
[door creaks]
STYLE
::cue()
[Cheoljung] So I heard you sold a watch
to Mr. Jang a week ago.
For 30 million.
[exhales]
How much did you pay for it?
You were able to sell for a high price.
And you didn't tell me.
[Mr. Jang clears throat]
I mean, I thought the price was, well,
a little too high.
So I let Han know.
All right, bring me the ledger.
[Cheoljung] I said bring me the ledger.
[♪ suspenseful music]
[exhales]
What else did you say you took?
[Mr. Jang] That's all for this month.
Wait, actually,
I bought a few rings, too.
I think she priced those correctly.
[Mr. Jang chuckles]
You said you got diamonds.
'Bout a month ago.
[Cheoljung exhales]
No diamonds.
Not even one.
Is there a separate ledger for Janggak?
[book lands on desk]
[cigarette sizzles]
You can go home now.
[groans]
I hope I didn't say anything that
was unnecessary.
No, you were right to.
I'm the owner and the husband.
-Best that I know everything.
-Right.
[Cheoljung] All right, then.
Take care.
[Cheoljung exhales]
Uh, I'll see you.
[Cheoljung] Goodbye.
[door creaks]
[locks click]
[cigarette sizzles]
[exhales]
[Cheoljung] You must
have really lost your mind.
[inhales on cigarette]
You were just a coffee shop girl
with a little kid.
I took you in and fed you,
and you thank me
by taking my money on the sly?
[inhales]
[exhales]
[stomps out cigarette]
When did this start?
How much have you skimmed now?
-That's all.
-[Sunok] Oh.
Really?
[Cheoljung exhales sharply]
You thieving bitch.
Look at you still lying through
your fucking teeth!
[slams hand on table]
[Cheoljung] Shit!
-[panicked breathing]
-[grunting]
Where do you think you're going?
-[screaming]
-[Cheoljung] Come here!
[both shouting]
[filing cabinet bangs]
[Sunok groaning]
Better not say you fucking spent it all.
If you did, I swear I'll
send you straight to Heaven.
[gasping]
I swear.
[gagging]
[Sunok struggling]
Hah!
[groaning]
[gasps]
You won't say?
[Cheoljung] You know I won't hesitate
to cut you.
I am gonna check the ledgers.
So why don't you just spit it out,
fucking bitch?
[blow lands]
[groans]
-[Cheoljung groans]
-[Sunok gasps]
No, Heeju!
No, don't do it.
[Heeju whimpering]
[Sunok gasps]
[blood squelching]
[both breathing heavily]
[Sunok] Go.
Hurry, hurry, go.
Look at me and get a hold of yourself!
Just grab what you need and go.
I'll take care of everything.
STYLE
::cue()
[drawers clanging]
[both breathing heavily]
[Sunok] Take this.
It's the money I've earned over the years.
I've been saving it for you.
So take it and don't ever come back.
[Sunok] No matter what happens to me,
don't try to look for me.
Don't try to find out.
You go somewhere far away.
I want you to live a good life.
No.
You have to go.
I'm really sorry.
Heeju.
[Sunok] I'm sorry.
I need you to listen.
Just listen to me this once.
Go! You going will save my life.
[Sunok] Go. Go!
[Heeju] Auntie! Auntie!
-[Sunok] Go!
-[Heeju] Auntie!
[Heeju crying]
I told you to go! Go!
Hurry up and get outta here!
[Sunok] I said go away! Go!
[both crying]
[whimpering]
[sniffling]
[cell phone trilling]
[receiver clicks]
[gasps]
Hello.
I-I'm in Bukju.
[Sunok] The Happy Pawnshop in Bukju.
[Sunok] I think I killed a person.
[crying]
[distant sirens wailing]
[sirens approaching]
[tires squeaking]
[more sirens approaching]
[brakes squeaking]
Auntie.
[crying]
Mom.
[sirens wailing]
[Heeju crying]
[♪ dramatic music]
[♪ dramatic music continues]